<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/SHIELDBlog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/SHIELDBlog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-11-10T13:33:27+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/SHIELDBlog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">SHIELD PROJECT BLOG</title><entry><title type="html">Introduction</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/SHIELDBlog/Posts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introduction" /><published>2020-03-01T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-03-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/SHIELDBlog/Posts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/SHIELDBlog/Posts/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/shield_navbar.png&quot; alt=&quot;Project Image&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; height: auto;&quot; /&gt;
Nowadays, cybercrime is one of the most relevant and critical threats to both the economy and society in Europe. Establishing efficient and effective ways to protect services and infrastructures from ever-evolving cyber threats is crucial for sustaining business integrity and reputation as well as protecting personal and sensitive data.
To that end, the SHIELD project proposes a universal solution for dynamically establishing and deploying virtual security infrastructures into ISP and corporate networks. SHIELD builds on the huge momentum of Network Functions Virtualisation (NFV), as currently standardised by ETSI, in order to virtualise security appliances into virtual Network Security Functions (vNSFs), to be instantiated within the network infrastructure using NFV technologies and concepts, effectively monitoring and filtering network traffic in a distributed manner.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Nowadays, cybercrime is one of the most relevant and critical threats to both the economy and society in Europe. Establishing efficient and effective ways to protect services and infrastructures from ever-evolving cyber threats is crucial for sustaining business integrity and reputation as well as protecting personal and sensitive data. To that end, the SHIELD project proposes a universal solution for dynamically establishing and deploying virtual security infrastructures into ISP and corporate networks. SHIELD builds on the huge momentum of Network Functions Virtualisation (NFV), as currently standardised by ETSI, in order to virtualise security appliances into virtual Network Security Functions (vNSFs), to be instantiated within the network infrastructure using NFV technologies and concepts, effectively monitoring and filtering network traffic in a distributed manner.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Scope and Benefits of SHIELD project</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/SHIELDBlog/Posts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Scope and Benefits of SHIELD project" /><published>2020-02-01T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-02-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/SHIELDBlog/Posts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/SHIELDBlog/Posts/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/benefits.png&quot; alt=&quot;Project Image&quot; style=&quot;width: 75%; height: auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vendor-neutral Security-as-a-Service offering&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open and scalable solution&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fully expandable with third party vNSF and analytics algorithms&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In-line with emerging technologies and trends&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Suitable for SMEs, big enterprices and ISPs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Vendor-neutral Security-as-a-Service offering Open and scalable solution Fully expandable with third party vNSF and analytics algorithms In-line with emerging technologies and trends Suitable for SMEs, big enterprices and ISPs</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">System Components</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/SHIELDBlog/Posts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="System Components" /><published>2020-01-01T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-01-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/SHIELDBlog/Posts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/SHIELDBlog/Posts/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/schema.png&quot; alt=&quot;Project Image&quot; style=&quot;width: 80%; height: auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VIRTUAL NETWORK SECURITY FUNCTIONS (VNSFS)&lt;/strong&gt;: vNSFs are instantiated within the network infrastructure by a vNSF orchestrator in order to effectively monitor and filter network traffic in a distributed manner.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DATA ANALYSIS AND REMEDIATION ENGINE (DARE)&lt;/strong&gt;: an information-driven IDPS platform capable ofpredicting specific vulnerabilities and attacks by relying on Big Data, Threat Monitoring and Machine Learning to analyse the output produced by vNSFs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TRUSTED INFRASTRUCTURE&lt;/strong&gt;: The infrastructure attestation binds the vNSFs and the network configuration with the store and orchestration of the network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">VIRTUAL NETWORK SECURITY FUNCTIONS (VNSFS): vNSFs are instantiated within the network infrastructure by a vNSF orchestrator in order to effectively monitor and filter network traffic in a distributed manner. DATA ANALYSIS AND REMEDIATION ENGINE (DARE): an information-driven IDPS platform capable ofpredicting specific vulnerabilities and attacks by relying on Big Data, Threat Monitoring and Machine Learning to analyse the output produced by vNSFs. TRUSTED INFRASTRUCTURE: The infrastructure attestation binds the vNSFs and the network configuration with the store and orchestration of the network</summary></entry></feed>